<resources>
    <string name="app_name">healthGuide</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Close</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="title_activity_newrecord">newrecord</string>
    <string name="diet">
        We should not restrict diet for these children, rather we should give normal healthy diet with lot of variety and match it with insulin dose.
        Carb exchanges as advised by dietician are very important to have variety in meals.
        Foods rich in sugars and fat should be restricted.
        These include chocolates, pastries, ice cream, sweet biscuits, fried items, chips and carbonated beverages like pepsi, cola etc.
        Encourage intake of fibre rich foods like raw vegetables, fruits and whole grains.Having a regular diet schedule helps in sugar control.
        It is important to remember that occasional excesses are allowed, as in parties and weddings, provided the meal and insulin are planned so that the child does not become rebellious and start eating stealthily.
    </string>
    <string name="act">
        Physical activity is an important part of the treatment of diabetes.
        Regular physical activity helps in improving sugar control, physical fitness, muscle strength and psychological well being of the child.
        Activity consumes sugar and thus low sugar is a frequent consequence.
    </string>
    <string name="doctorvisit">
        Once a child is on a particular insulin regimen, sugars are stable and parents are confident, 3 monthly visits with HbA1c levels are sufficient.
        More frequent visits may be necessary in the initial phase after diagnosis, when sugars are fluctuating and when insulin regimen is changed.
    </string>
    <string name="fluctuation">
A very tight control of sugars is neither possible nor desirable, especially in younger children in whom there is a risk of brain damage because of low sugars.
        In older children, mild to moderately low sugars occurring say 3-4 times in a month is an indicator of good control.
    </string>
    <string name="mealplan">
        Meal plan for different age groups for different meals are suggested in the diet chart attached.
        Modifications can be done seeing the options available for same amount of carb containing exchanges.
    </string>
    <string name="monitor">
        Weight and height of the child is checked every visit (3 monthly).
        A child growing normally means diabetes control is fair to good. BP is monitored at least every year.
        HbA1c is monitored every 3 monthly (it is not required to be done after fasting).
        Thyroid function test and test for wheat allergy has to be done every year.
        After 3-5 years of diagnosis of type 1 diabetes or after 11 yrs of age, screening tests for chronic complications of diabetes are to be done.
        Screening for retinopathy should start from age 11 years and after two years diabetes duration.
        Annual screening for microalbuminuria should start from age 11 years and after 5 years diabetes duration (24 hour urine collection for micro albumin).
        Screening for fasting blood lipids should be performed when diabetes is diagnosed in children aged over 10 years.
        If normal results are obtained, screening should be repeated every 5 years (if abnormal every year).
        Peripheral and autonomic neuropathy should be assessed by history and physical examination from age 11 years with two years diabetes duration.
    </string>
    <string name="sites">
        Insulin injection is given under the skin in the fat (subcutaneous).
        It is absorbed fastest from abdomen followed by arms, thighs and buttocks in that order.
        Also insulin is absorbed fast from the part which is being exercised (e.g. from thighs if someone starts walking/jogging after taking insulin shot in thigh).
        Because of difference in absorption from different sites, a proper rotation plan for injection should be followed.
        Generally one can use one site for 10 days with rotation within the site,so that in 30 days we rotate between 3 sites i.e.
        arms (5 days on each side), abdomen (10 days, by rotation 1.5-2 inches away from umbilicus) and thighs (5 days on each side).
        Rotation is important because insulin injection causes damage to the skin (lipodystrophy) if given at the same site over long period.
        This will lead to poor absorption of insulin.
    </string>
    <string name="storage">
        All insulin vials or pen injections which are currently in use (opened) can be safely kept at room temperature (below 30 degrees) for up to 1 month.
        All sealed Insulin vials or pen refills/cartridges kept for backup should be stored in fridge at 2-8 degrees (lower shelf or door of fridge) i.e. they should never be frozen (if frozen, one has to discard).
        During journey by train or bus, they can easily be kept in a bag at cool dry space without excesses of temperature (not near engines of bus/car).
        There is no need to keep icepacks until there are very high temperatures.
    </string>

    <string-array name="comments">
        <item>before Breakfast</item>
        <item>after Breakfast</item>
        <item>before Lunch</item>
        <item>after Lunch</item>
        <item>before Dinner</item>
        <item>after Dinner</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
